<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Grey Wall IT</title>
    <link>https://GreyWallIT.github.io/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Grey Wall IT</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 21:45:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://GreyWallIT.github.io/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Windows Admin Center on Windows Server Core</title>
      <link>https://GreyWallIT.github.io/windows/installwacsrvcore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 21:45:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://GreyWallIT.github.io/windows/installwacsrvcore/</guid>
      <description>The Windows Admin Center is a free tool from Microsoft that I like to think of as the next iteration of Windows Server Manager or the RSAT tools. It lets you manage your servers, clusters, hyper-converged infrastructure, Windows 10 computers, and a host of other features and functions come with that. If you have co-workers that manage servers but are intimidated by the command line it makes it difficult to be able to deploy Windows Server Core in your environment as it may lessen the ability of the team to manage those servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting PowerShell as the Default Shell in Server Core</title>
      <link>https://GreyWallIT.github.io/windows/powershelldefaultservercore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 20:52:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://GreyWallIT.github.io/windows/powershelldefaultservercore/</guid>
      <description>The default shell for Windows Server Core is the command prompt. Ideally you will change that to PowerShell so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to manually run PowerShell if you ever need to RDP into the server. To make this change login to your server core machine and run PowerShell:
C:\windows\system32\powershell.exeEdit the registry to set PowerShell as the default Shell:
Set-ItemProperty -Path &#39;HKLM:\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Windows NT\CurrentVersion\Winlogon&#39; -Name Shell -Value &#39;powershell.exe&#39;The next time you login the shell will immediately run PowerShell.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>